<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel>
<title>Verstappen.nl - News</title>
<link>http://www.verstappen.nl/</link>
<description>Verstappen.nl - News</description>
<atom:link href="http://www.verstappen.nl/rss/nieuwsen.php" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<image>
	<url>http://www.verstappen.nl/images/max_logo.png</url>
	<title>Verstappen.nl - News</title>
	<link>http://www.verstappen.nl/</link>
</image>
 

<item>
<title>Max fifteenth in FP1: "Still work to do"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2478&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen opened his Russian Grand Prix weekend with P15 in the first free practice session. Nico Rosberg clocked the quickest time on the Sochi track with team mate Lewis Hamilton and Ferrari ace Sebastian Vettel completing the top three.</p>

<p>“There’s still work to do”, says Max to Verstappen.nl. “The car doesn’t have a lot of grip on the slippery and dusty track. The circuit is always ‘green’ during the first session which also affects the grip. We’ll now analyse the data to improve the set-up for the second free practice.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Apr 2016 09:35:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Rusland_-_Sochi/P-20160429-00116_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-9c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2478&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Column: Jos Verstappen - Criticising Hamilton is too easy</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2477&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Jos Verstappen is still the Netherlands most successful Formula 1-driver. This season also, he shares his opinions regarding the sport via a column in the Dutch daily newspaper <em>De Telegraaf. </em>Below the latest edition.</p>

<p>"The Sochi circuit in the Olympic Park still has an atmosphere of the previous winter Olympics. When I joined Max on his track walk on Wednesday, I noticed how tidy and colourful – the numerous flags really add to that – the place looks. In that respect I'm impressed with what the Russians achieved here. It cost a lot and it looks like the facilities aren’t used that often, but the place does have allure that suits Formula 1.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/18032016-AUS-3023-31c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2477&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max: "Qualifying P5 in Sochi is not realistic"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2476&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen is hoping for a positive weekend in Russia as he described the qualities you need to tackle the Sochi track. "You're aiming to have a clean lap with not too much oversteer," said the Dutchman. "You need to hit the apexes, as the majority of corners are 90 degrees and all pretty similar. You also need good top speed and, even if we know we are not the fastest down the straights, we will be trying our best to make up time in the corners, but with 90 degree turns that is a difficult task.” </p>

<p>Max continues: “Getting the tyres working properly will be a challenge: it was already difficult last year but this time we can expect cooler temperatures, making it even harder. On paper, you'd be aiming to get away with a one-stop strategy, but that's not so straightforward with the new 70% tread factor introduced this season. So, on the tyre side, we will have to wait and see after the second and third free practice sessions."</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Apr 2016 18:22:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/16042016-CHI-3028-18f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2476&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Predicts Max' fastest lap and win the Verstappen Exact cap!</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2472&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with the Verstappen web shop, Verstappen.nl has issued a contest in which the Max Verstappen driver’s cap (priced at € 34,95) can be won during this fourth round of the season. The cap, featuring the Exact logo, can only be purchased from the Verstappen webshop.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Apr 2016 12:10:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Algemene_Max_Fotos/STR16024-3e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2472&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>John Booth to work with Scuderia Toro Rosso</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2475&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Scuderia Toro Rosso has announced that, with immediate effect, John Booth will begin working with the Italian team on a consultancy basis in the role of director of racing. The Englishman, who has wide ranging experience in all forms of motorsport, including Formula 1, will take up his responsibilities as from this weekend's Russian Grand Prix.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 26 Apr 2016 15:11:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160302-00341_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-20f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2475&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max: "After strong result in China, I hope for good result in Sochi"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2474&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Looking ahead to the Russian Grand Prix, Max says: “The first thing I remember from Russia is my good qualifying! It's always good to start the race from the highest spot possible and starting P9 in Russia meant already being in the point's positions… Even though we unfortunately didn't have a good start in the race: I arrived to turn 1 and Hulkenberg spun in front of me, we collided in turn 2 and I had a puncture. It wasn't great, as I had damage on the car and it all got very tricky but I still tried to do my best.” In the end Max finished tenth.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 26 Apr 2016 14:50:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160414-00356_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-34c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2474&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>STR Olym-PicknMix Games: round 4</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2473&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>As the 2016 F1 season gets underway, Scuderia Toro Rosso introduces the “STR Olym-PicknMix Games”: Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz will pick a different challenge each time and go head to head in 21 games. Before each Grand Prix this season, a new battle between the two youngsters will be available to watch. Below the fourth round!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 26 Apr 2016 14:29:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160415-00153_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-9c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2473&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tost after Chinese GP: "Satisfying result"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2471&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Franz Tost, team principal of Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after the Chinese race: “The Chinese Grand Prix was a very exciting race from start to finish. Both Max and Carlos did a really good start, but unfortunately Max lost some places in the first corner as he had to back off because of the crash between the two Ferraris. Carlos was in a good position until the safety car came out when he was then heavily stopped by Hulkenberg, who slowed down massively in the pit-lane and this caused us to lose a lot of places. Nevertheless, both drivers were able to catch-up and crossed the line in P8 and P9 – a very satisfying result. Both cars scored points, we showed that the car is competitive and that the team and drivers did a good job. I’d like to thank everyone for this and we are now looking forward to the race in Sochi where we also expect quite a good performance from our side.” </p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Apr 2016 11:09:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Algemene_Autosport_fotos/P-20160417-00067_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-7c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2471&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max 8th in a catch-up race in China: "Very pleased"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2470&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen finished in eighth during the Chinese Grand Prix in a race that had a troubled opening. The start of the race was very tumultuous, as the safety car jostled the entire field. Nico Rosberg drove unthreatened to victory in front of Sebastian Vettel’s Ferrari and both Red Bulls, in which Daniil Kvyat claimed P3 ahead of Daniel Ricciardo in fourth.</p>

<p>“When the lights turned green, I reacted fast enough, but the car was in the wrong power mode, causing me to not have full power. That was my mistake”, Max explains to Verstappen.nl about his start. “I lost some positions because of that and also during the first pit stop, when both Sainz and I came in together, I lost more. Which put me at the back of a string of cars. That’s when I thought ‘this is not working as planned’. But I remained calm, didn’t get frustrated, fought my way back and overtook them one by one.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Apr 2016 09:21:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160416-00226_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-31f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2470&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>James Key: "A very eventful day"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2469&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>James Key, Technical Director of Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after qualifying on Saturday in China: “A very eventful day. Today’s qualifying was an exciting session, with a lot going on. I think we come away happy to have both cars through to top ten relatively easily but a little bit frustrated that we didn’t really pull it together with the final runs in Q3. Both cars lost quite a bit of time in the third sector during their final run, which means that we are 8th and 9th when I think we could’ve been a little bit higher than that.”</p>

<p>“We clearly need to look into this and understand what happened, but it’s history now and our immediate priority is to move on and concentrate on preparation for the race. There are several strategies that need to be considered given the combination of tyres available so there may be some different approaches tomorrow. It’s also a bit difficult to predict because conditions look like they will be pretty warm so we will need to consider how this may affect the tyres and what implications there are for our plans.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Apr 2016 11:04:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/_JMP4675-10f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2469&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max not unhappy with P9 in Chinese GP qualifying</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2468&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen will start the Chinese Grand Prix from ninth. The Dutchman qualified in the top ten for the third consecutive time on a partially damp track. Pole position was once again for Mercedes with Nico Rosberg claiming top spot. Daniel Ricciardo surprised with P2 ahead of Kimi Raikkonen and Sebastian Vettel.</p>

<p>“I'm not unhappy. Of course you always hope for a better result, but we were in the top ten again, which is always important”, said Max to Verstappen.nl. “I definitely see possibilities to get a better result in the race. A lot will depend on strategy so I'm looking forward to an interesting race.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Apr 2016 09:15:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160415-00219_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-16c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2468&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max P9 in China: "Curious about the qualifying"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2467&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>During a wet third free practice, in the run up to the Chinese Grand Prix, Max Verstappen noted the ninth fastest time. On the 5,451 meters long Shanghai International Circuit, it was Sebastian Vettel in his Ferrari who was the fastest in front of Valtteri Bottas. Sergio Perez claimed the third spot in his Force India.</p>

<p>“It is a pity that we were not able to do that many laps because of the rain”, Max informed Verstappen.nl. “As oppose to many others, I drove with a race set up. It’s in the qualifying that it it will matter, shortly. I am curious.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Apr 2016 06:38:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160416-00043_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-1f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2467&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Phil Charles: "Very satisfied after Friday" </title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2466&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Phil Charles, chief race engineer at Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after Friday in Shanghai: “China is usually a real challenge. Firstly, the tyres have a very hard time and, as engineers, we are on tender hooks to see if the front-left grains badly or not. On top of this, it is very technically tricky for the drivers too and they can have a massive impact on how the tyres behave." </p>

<p>"Today lived up to those China sentiments. We saw some interesting patterns of behaviour across the three tyre compounds, especially in the long runs. We will be going through the data carefully tonight with the drivers to best understand how to make them work for Sunday. On our side we are pretty happy having worked through most of our program checklist and both drivers having settled in well. We will also be watching the weather forecast for tomorrow very keenly tonight as there may be some rain to give us some more entertainment!”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Apr 2016 09:36:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160302-00334_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-19f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2466&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max sixth in FP2: "Reasonably happy"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2465&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen finished sixth in the second free practice session of the Chinese Grand Prix. The Dutchman trailed the front running Ferraris of Sebastian Vettel and Kimi Raikkonen by 1.3 seconds. Both Mercedes, for once not topping the leader boards, followed the Ferraris in third and fourth.</p>

<p>“It went ok. The balance of the car was better than in FP1 so that’s positive”, said Max to Verstappen.nl. “The difference between the medium and the super-soft Pirellis is pretty big. To be able to instantly do a quick lap on the super-softs is challenging but it looked good.”<br />
<br />
With rain forecast for qualifying, Max heads into an interesting Saturday: “I’m curious how we’ll do in a wet qualifying. It’s all very close but our long runs are pretty good so I’m reasonably happy.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Apr 2016 08:36:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160415-00203_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-14c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2465&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Column: Jos Verstappen - Max wants to score 100 points</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2463&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Jos Verstappen is still the Netherlands most successful Formula 1-driver. This season he shares his opinions regarding the sport via a column in Dutch daily newspaper <em>De Telegraaf. </em>Below the latest edition.</p>

<p>“Max’ sixth place in Bahrain was better than we had all expected. Toro Rosso always had difficult races there in the past. Although we were less strong during qualifying, the final result was just super. The team particularly praised the way Max took care of his tyres. But when I talked to him about that afterwards, he said: ‘Dad, I always take care of the tyres, but that also depends on how the car responds and our strategy.’ Everything fell nicely into its place. That was somehow needed by the way, given the disappointment of the first Grand Prix.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/14042016-CHI-1007-3c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2463&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max tenth in chaotic China FP1</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2464&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen started his Chinese Grand Prix weekend with P10 in the first free practice session. Nico Rosberg topped the timing sheets, two seconds faster than the Dutchman in his Scuderia Toro Rosso. Lewis Hamilton and Sebastian Vettel completed the top three. Despite the usual suspects at the business of the leader boards, it was a chaotic FP1, which was twice interrupted at length by red flag situations caused by punctures.<br />
<br />
“It's a shame we weren’t able to do many laps due to the two red flags. The track was also dirty with a lot of sand”, explains Max to Verstappen.nl. “In the last six minutes I was able to do some laps on the softer tyres but due to a small technical issue I lost some time. I think it will all be fine. The car isn’t optimal yet, but we'll work on that so I'm looking forward to FP2.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Apr 2016 05:03:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160415-00073_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-1e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2464&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max looks ahead to Chinese GP: "Top five would be great"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2462&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Looking back at the previous Grand Prix, Max Verstappen said on Thursday in Shanghai: “Bahrain was definitely very positive for me and for the team and the result was slightly unexpected. It was good to score mine and Toro Rosso's first points at that track. Apart from that, I was also pleased that I had a very clean race with no mistakes.”</p>

<p>After just two races, Max is optimistic about how his car will develop over the coming season. “There is definitely more to come from the car and, at this point of the year we are still working to understand more about it, which is the same for all teams and the same as happens every year”, explained Max. “But the general feeling I have is that the car reacts well to inputs and we have quite a competitive package. In Bahrain we had it set up just right, so now we must concentrate on doing that at every Grand Prix.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Apr 2016 18:04:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/14042016-CHI-1011-5c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2462&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Predicts Max' fastest lap and win a STR team polo!</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2461&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with the Verstappen web shop, Verstappen.nl has issued a contest in which the official 2016 Scuderia Toro Rosso teamline polo (priced at € 64,95) can be won during this third round of the season. This polo and other Max Verstappen and Toro Rosso merchandise can be purchased from the Verstappen webshop.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Apr 2016 11:18:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Algemene_Max_Fotos/2016_Max_merch_2-2c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2461&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Video: Catcher Car training for Wings for Life World Run with Max and Carlos</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2460&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If Max Verstappen or Carlos Sainz told you to run faster, you would, right? Well, that’s exactly what they’ll do on May 8, 2016. They join 32 Catcher Car drivers as the motivation for tens of thousands of Wings for Life World Runners in 34 international locations to run as far and as fast as they can, chased by the Catcher Cars.</p>

<p>Like Verstappen, Sainz and David Coulthard, the Catcher Car drivers worldwide have spent decades in high-speed, high-focus disciplines to prepare themselves for this moment. With endurance, precision and absolute dexterity learnt at high speed, they will slow right down to maintain a synchronised crawling speed to chase thousands of runners worldwide.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Apr 2016 12:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Wings_for_Life_filmopnames/JS_WINGS_FOR_LIFE_CLIP_260316_0023-1c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2460&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max: "Had some good overtakes in China"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2459&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>“I like China, I remember I had some good overtakes there! The first four corners of the circuit, turns 1 to 4, are a very special part and tricky to get right. Another part of the track that I enjoyed last year was turn 6… I did a good move there! I couldn't overtake Perez on the straight, so I had to do it somewhere else… I got a good exit out of turn 5 and, approaching turn 6, where you normally brake late – as it's a hairpin – I managed to overtake him by braking even later than usual. It's a big relief when you finally get passed a rival and I was very happy.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Apr 2016 15:13:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/03042016-BHR-4188-36c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2459&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>STR Olym-PicknMix Games: round 3</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2458&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>As the 2016 F1 season gets underway, Scuderia Toro Rosso introduces the “STR Olym-PicknMix Games”: Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz will pick a different challenge each time and go head to head in 21 games. Before each Grand Prix this season, a new battle between the two youngsters will be available to watch. Below the third round!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Apr 2016 14:55:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/P-20160402-00155_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-33c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2458&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max drives a solid race in Bahrain: "Great to finish in 6th"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2457&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen finished in sixth during the Bahrain Grand Prix in a thrilling race. Even though he barely managed to clinch a top ten position, after having good free practices on Friday and qualifying on Saturday. But with this feat the youngster gets even for the false start of the season’s opener in Australia, two weeks ago. The eight points earned, are the first Scuderia Toro Rosso has even scored in Sakhir. On the Bahrain International Circuit, Nico Rosberg won the race in his Mercedes, ahead of the Ferrari driving Kimi Raikkonen. Reigning world champion, Lewis Hamilton, came in third in his Mercedes.</p>

<p>Immediately after the race, a cheerful Max talks to Verstappen.nl: “It was a great race. It is fantastic to finish in sixth here, all the more that this isn’t a circuit that suits us well. It went much better, than we anticipated before the weekend. The choices we made yesterday, paid off during the race. This is a track where you can overtake very well and I had some great moves. Unfortunately we couldn’t catch Grosjean anymore at the end. The tyres were working well, the car was handling fine, the pit stops and strategy were super. The whole team did a great job and I had a lot of fun today!”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Apr 2016 18:29:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/01042016-BHR-2100-20f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2457&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Franz Tost: "P6 a good result"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2456&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Franz Tost, Team Principal of Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after the race in Bahrain: “Taking into consideration that we started today’s race from P10 and P11, to finish with a car in P6 is, on one side, a really good result but, on the other, it’s a pity we had to retire the other car. I’d like to congratulate Max and the team, because both parties did a really good and professional job, both regarding strategy and pit-stops.”</p>

<p>“Unfortunately, Carlos had a collision with Perez, which caused a puncture on the right-rear tyre at the beginning of his lap. As a result of this, while driving back to the pits, the floor also got damaged… We therefore ended up deciding to call him in, even though originally we made him stay out just in case there was a Safety Car period. This never happened so we ended his race prematurely as the car was very unstable in the rear because of the amount of downforce we had lost. On a more positive note, this is the first time we score points here in Bahrain, so we can be happy with this, and we now look forward to China, where we expect to be quite competitive.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Apr 2016 18:23:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/_JMP4659-8c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2456&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Key: "We have a little bit of an advantage"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2455&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>James Key, technical director at Scuderia Toro Rosso, commented after qualifying in Bahrein: "We knew that out of the first four events this year, Bahrain was always going to be the trickiest one for us and unfortunately this proved to be the case today. This is a stop-start track, where longitudinal performance is a bigger player than lateral performance, and we are weaker in longitudinal than lateral... So it's not playing to the strengths of our car as much as other circuits will be. The nature of this track is also to pull the field a lot closer and so it was very tight between teams today."</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Apr 2016 18:45:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2015/Key_People_Toro_Rosso_2015/James_Key_Franz_Tost-5f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2455&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Verstappen qualifies in tenth: "A good result"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2454&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen will start the Bahrain Grand Prix from tenth on the grid, one place ahead of team mate Carlos Sainz. Both Toro Rossos will therefore have the option to choose the tyre compound ahead of the race. Pole position was once again for Mercedes with Lewis Hamilton beating Nico Rosberg to lock out the front row ahead of the two Ferraris.</p>

<p>“Of course you always want to be further up the grid but on this track it's a good result”, said Max to Verstappen.nl. “It's not a track that suits our car that much so to be this close to Q3 is good. I also didn’t have enough tyres to go out for another lap. I would've liked to, but in the end we can be very happy with tenth. In Q2 it's always difficult to judge where you're going to end up. You would rather be ninth then eighth so we're pretty happy with today."</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Apr 2016 16:31:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/P-20160402-00237_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-41e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2454&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Verstappen P15 in FP3: "Really useful long run"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2453&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In the final free practice session ahead of qualifying for the Bahrain Grand Prix, Max Verstappen finished in P15. The two Scuderia Toro Rosso drivers, both hindered by small technical issues, were among the few drivers that opted out of using the super soft tyres for their quickest laps. At the front, the Ferrari duo of Sebastian Vettel and Kimi Raikkonen led the way, four tenths ahead of both Mercedes.</p>

<p>“It might not look fast, but that's because we did a long run on a high fuel load”, explains Max to Verstappen.nl “We had a different programme than most teams. I also had a problem which meant I had to come into the pits. The team fixed it, although I'm not sure what the issue was. It meant I was able to finish my long run, which was really useful.”</p>

<p>In the second half of the session the Dutchman set quicker times. “At the end we went out on the softs, not the super softs like the rest of the teams. That's why that time wasn't really representative. But it's going to be very close in qualifying. Anything can happen between P5 and P14.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Apr 2016 13:33:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/01042016-BHR-2007-2e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2453&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Phil Charles: "A really interesting day" </title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2452&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Phil Charles, chief race engineer of Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after Friday in Bahrain: “A really interesting day. We started the cars with quite similar set-ups but through the two sessions we have split the cars in several ways to try to put together a picture for the rest of the weekend. In free practice 2 we had Carlos long-running the medium and Max the soft tyre. As engineers we now have quite a busy night with plenty of homework to do!"</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Apr 2016 19:34:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160303-00257_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-41c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2452&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max fourth in Bahrain's second free practice: "It looks positive"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2451&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen started the Friday in Bahrain excellently. After finishing in eighth during the first free practice, the 18-year old Formula 1-driver positioned himself quite neatly in fourth in the second practice. Nico Rosberg and Lewis Hamilton were, once again, flawless and were a second up on Jenson Button (McLaren) in their Mercedes. Max was able to stay ahead of Kimi Raikkonen (P5) and Sebastian Vettel (P6) in their Ferrari’s.</p>

<p>“This is a good start of the weekend”, as Max starts talking to Verstappen.nl. “The track conditions were different now and of course we need to improve many things, but it is definitely a good start. We were able to run and work on the set-up of the car, so that is very positive.” Does the Bahrain track suit the STR11 as well? “It’s going well now, but we are trying to stay grounded because we do not know what others have tested. We will need to keep improving, just like the others. But for now, it definitely looks positive.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Apr 2016 18:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/P-20160401-00627_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-5e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2451&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max kicks off Bahrain GP in eighth: "Still some work to do"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2450&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen clocked the eighth fastest time in the first free practice session of the Bahrain Grand Prix. The Scuderia Toro Rosso driver trailed fastest man Nico Rosberg by 2.5 seconds. The German finished the session on top ahead of Mercedes team mate Lewis Hamilton and Ferrari’s Kimi Raikkonen.</p>

<p>“It went pretty well. We took our time to pick up the pace and familiarize ourselves”, said Max to Verstappen.nl. “The conditions weren’t optimal because of the sand and dust on the track. Nevertheless we worked on improving our set-up. It isn’t yet how we want it to be so we’ll have some work to do. But it was good to have driven here again.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Apr 2016 13:45:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/P-20160401-00477_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-1f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2450&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Column: Jos Verstappen - Criticism should be kept indoors</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2449&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Jos Verstappen is still the Netherlands most successful Formula 1-driver. This season also, he shares his opinions regarding the sport via a column in the Dutch daily newspaper <em>De Telegraaf. </em>Below the latest edition.</p>

<p>“The Bahrain Grand Prix is just around the corner, but the aftermath of the first race of this season in Australia is still noticeable. It is obvious that both Max as his team, had higher expectations of the race in Melbourne.<br />
<br />
Max was on the receiving end of a lot of criticism because of his falling out with his team on the radio during the race. His remarks were a result of his frustration and anger on how the race was progressing and decisions made by the team, but I am, in no way, condoning the way he reacted. It was the first time Max did something like that and I spoke extensively with him about it. He knows very well that something like that is not appropriate and not done. It is also not professional for a Formula 1-driver. Criticism, you keep to yourself and after the race, you talk about it. Indoors, with the team. And not through the media.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/18032016-AUS-3023-31f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2449&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max happy with new starting procedure: "I can handle it well."</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2448&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>During the FIA press conference prior to the Bahrain Grand Prix, Fernando Alonso received the most question. The Spaniard will sit out the second round of the championship after the FIA deemed him not fit enough to race after his horror crash in the season opener in Melbourne. His replacement will be the Stoffel Vandoorne, the reigning GP2 champion. The Belgian will make his F1 debut this weekend.</p>

<p>Max Verstappen was also present at the press conference. After a tumultuous race in Australia, the press want to know what Max had learned from Melbourne. “First of all we had a great qualifying, so we can be happy with that. But of course the race didn’t work out like we wanted to. We analysed everything and hopefully we can get back stronger here in Bahrain. Even though this track hasn’t suited Toro Rosso in the past, we’ll give it our best, that’s for sure.”  </p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 31 Mar 2016 13:58:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/P-20160320-00081_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-8f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2448&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Predicts Max' fastest lap and win a STR sweat jacket!</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2447&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with the Verstappen web shop, Verstappen.nl has issued a contest in which the official 2016 Scuderia Toro Rosso teamline sweat jacket (priced at € 84,95) can be won during this second round of the season. This sweat jacket and other Max Verstappen and Toro Rosso merchandise can be purchased from the Verstappen webshop.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:18:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/18032016-AUS-3025-32f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2447&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max targets points in Bahrain GP</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2446&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen previews the Bahrain GP: “The Bahrain circuit has a very long straight – too long last year! – and they overtook me quite a few times there in 2015… It's not a nice feeling and inside your head you're talking to yourself and saying ‘c'mon, c'mon!’. It's frustrating, but there's not much more you can do when another car is quicker than you.”</p>

<p>“I also remember a lot of national flags on the left after the first three turns. I first saw them during the track walk, but then I sometimes also had time to see them while driving. Turns 5, 6 and 7 were a bit tough to get right when it was dark as the braking points change, but it's still a nice part of the track as I always enjoy the fast corners.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 29 Mar 2016 09:42:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/18032016-AUS-3030-35f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2446&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>STR Olym-PicknMix Games: round 2</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2445&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>As the 2016 F1 season gets underway, Scuderia Toro Rosso introduces the “STR Olym-PicknMix Games”: Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz will pick a different challenge each time and go head to head in 21 games. Before each Grand Prix this season, a new battle between the two youngsters will be available to watch. Below the second round!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 29 Mar 2016 09:21:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Wings_for_Life_filmopnames/lekker-bezig-gap-3c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2445&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wings for Life brings Max and Carlos together</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2444&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A week prior to second Grand Prix of the season, Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz made time for an important cause: Wings for Life. Both Scuderia Toro Rosso drivers were filmed in the Netherlands for the running contest, which will be held in 33 countries on 8 May. In a relaxed and friendly manner, both team mates were up against each other.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Mar 2016 08:21:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Wings_for_Life_filmopnames/that-s-it-11f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2444&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max after Melbourne: "We had some miscommunications"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2443&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Looking back at the first Grand Prix in Melbourne, Max Verstappen is asked how his first race weekend of 2016 went. “I think generally the week started off well. We improved the car every time step‑by‑step, even though the conditions were not great with the rain and in order to save tyres. The qualifying was absolutely perfect.  To be fifth behind Mercedes and the Ferrari cars, that's definitely where we wanted to be. That was all great. I think we could be very happy with that.”</p>

<p>Max continues on Laureus.com, after the interview of today: “Then in the race, I think the start was good. First stint was also good. Then we had some miscommunications, I would say, and not a great finish.” Did the incident with team mate Carlos Sainz lead to rivalry? “To be honest, it doesn't really feel like such a thing. First of all, I'm always focusing ahead. So for me, to be honest, it doesn't really affect me as a struggle. We want to beat each other on track, but I think every driver wants to beat his team mate. And off‑track, everything is going well, so there are no issues there.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Mar 2016 20:09:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/16032017-AUS-2011-38f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2443&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max opts for different tyre allocation than Carlos</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2442&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Pirelli, Formula 1’s sole tyre supplier, has announced the teams’ tyre choices ahead of the Bahrain Grand Prix. From this season onwards, the Italian manufacturer supplies three different compound per weekend, instead of two. The drivers must use at least two of them during the race. Like the Australian Grand Prix, Pirelli will supply the medium, soft and super soft slicks. Each driver can choose up to thirteen sets of tyres per weekend. Their choice has to be made well in advance, three months prior to the Grand Prix.</p>

<p>Scuderia Toro Rosso’s drivers, Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz have chosen different strategies with the Dutchman opting for one set of the mediums, seven softs and five super softs. His Spanish team mate will be able to use one more of the medium compound and one less of the softs. Of all drivers, Max is the one with the most softs Pirellis.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Mar 2016 16:25:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/20032016-AUS-5100-42f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2442&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Franz Tost: "Disappointing result"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2441&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Franz Tost, team principle of Scuderia Toro Rosso, felt disappointed after the Australian Grand Prix: "Both drivers did a good start. Max came back from the first lap in 4th position, Carlos was 7th. We kept a fast pace in this first stint. Carlos’ pit-stop went well, by undercutting Massa. After the red flag, when the race was restarted, Max was 5th and Carlos 6th. But in the following laps we lost the pace. Carlos had a lot of front locking.  Therefore we called him for an early pit stop. We changed our strategy and sent him out on medium tires."</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Mar 2016 12:57:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/P-20160317-00139_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-12f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2441&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Verstappen tenth in hectic Australian GP: "Everything went wrong"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2440&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen scored his first point of the 2016 Formula 1 season. After a chaotic race, the Dutchman finished the Australian Grand Prix in tenth place. The Scuderia Toro Rosso driver was not able to capitalize on a excellent fifth place on the grid, after a slow second pit stop meant he rejoined the race in a bunged up midfield pack. At the front, Nico Rosberg claimed his fifteenth career win. The race was red flagged but later resumed after a severe crash involving McLaren's Fernando Alonso and Haas' Esteban Gutierrez. Both drivers walked away unharmed.</p>

<p>Straight after the race, Max is clear and concise in his commentary: “The start and first stint went well. But after the second pit stop it all went wrong.” The youngster refers to the miscommunication at the stop. “The tyres weren't ready and after that it became a difficult race. I was quicker than Sainz, throughout the whole race. Nothing was done about that so I know what I need to know.” </p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Mar 2016 08:12:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/P-20160320-00201_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-21e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2440&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>James Key: "P5 for Max is an excellent result"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2439&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>James Key, technical director of Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after the qualifying in Melbourne: “There were a lot of unknowns going into today in many respects. Firstly, it was not until today that we were able to run in dry conditions, so there was much to learn for all teams. Secondly, a new qualifying format and finally and most difficult to predict, to know exactly where everyone was, because winter testing is so difficult to predict. I think we did the right thing in free practice by trying to get some race data early on, as many other teams did, because clearly we were missing a lot of information due to yesterday’s weather conditions. This gave us some valuable data for tomorrow.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Mar 2016 09:50:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160301-01523_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-99c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2439&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Verstappen starts from fifth in first race 2016: "Very happy"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2438&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen finished in fifth during qualifying in the Australian GP, his best position in his still budding Formula 1-carreer. The Scuderia Toro Rosso-driver starts in Melbourne behind the Mercedes and Ferrari’s, no small feat. Lewis Hamilton snatched pole in the season’s openings race, ahead of his team mate Nico Rosberg.</p>

<p>“It went well. After the last free practice, during which the car’s balance wasn’t optimal, we changed the setup. We made the right choices and I am very happy with a fifth starting position", Max tells Verstappen.nl. “In this new qualifying setup, you only have one chance to do a good lap. There is immediately a lot of pressure on you, which makes it harder for everyone. Our strategy worked out well.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Mar 2016 08:31:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/P-20160319-00093_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-5f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2438&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Torro Rosso behind Mercedes and Ferrari in final practice Melbourne</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2437&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In the run up to the Australian GP, Scuderia Toro Rosso did an excellent job during the third and final free practice. With Max Verstappen in sixth and Carlos Sainz in fourth, the Italian squad was behind the likes of Mercedes and Ferrari as the ‘best of the rest’. Lewis Hamilton once again was at the front, ahead of his German team mate Nico Rosberg.</p>

<p>For the first time, it’s completely dry in Melbourne when the lights turn green for the third free practice. It is as busy as can get, from the word go. In all the commotion the teams were experiencing, in getting their cars on the grid, new kid on the block Rio Haryanto (Manor) and Romain Grosjean (Haas) ran into one another. They hit each other in the pit lane and damaged their cars.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Mar 2016 05:40:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/18032016-AUS-3072-49f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2437&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max plays no part in FP2: "Tricky conditions"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2436&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Having had an almost rained out first free practice earlier today, the second free practice was also driven in mixed conditions. Max never got round to driving in FP2, as it served no purpose in these conditions. Lewis Hamilton was once again the fastest in the second session, followed by Nico Hülkenberg in the Force India and Kimi Raikkonen in the Ferrari.</p>

<p>Max’ response at the end of the session is short and decisive. He tells Verstappen.nl: “It was a difficult day with tricky conditions. Because of those tricky conditions I wasn’t able to drive a lot, making it hard for me to draw a conclusion after the first day. I hope tomorrow will be dry, so we can finish our schedule and work on the setup of the car.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Mar 2016 09:01:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/P-20160318-00139_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-22c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2436&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Phil Charles: "First day back at school" </title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2435&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Phil Charles, chief race engineer of Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after Friday in Melbourne: “First day back at school! I had been looking forward to this day for a while as I expected it would be the first time this year where we would really start to learn where we rank as it is so difficult to judge in winter testing. Unfortunately the famous four-seasons-in-a-day Melbourne weather meant that we didn’t really get to fill in all of those question marks in either session.“</p>

<p>“Carlos had some problems in FP1 so we had to apologise to him after this morning’s session. On the positive side we managed to put those issues aside in FP2 and we managed three decent runs with him on intermediate tyres.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Mar 2016 08:37:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160303-00257_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-41c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2435&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Column: Jos Verstappen - Finally back in Melbourne</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2433&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Jos Verstappen is still the Netherlands most successful Formula 1-driver. This season he shares his opinions regarding the sport via a column in Dutch daily newspaper <em>De Telegraaf. </em>Below the latest edition.<br />
<br />
“We are in Melbourne again. At last. The F1-season's opener is always special. Because, first of all, it was a long wait and secondly, it now becomes apparent how the teams compare to one another.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Mar 2016 08:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2015/Formule_1_GP_Japan_-_Suzuka/JAP-240915-1002-8c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2433&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max starts off new season in P5 in a rainy Melbourne</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2434&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>After a firm debut for Scuderia Toro Rosso in 2015, and preseason testing that went well, Max Verstappen finally kicked off the new Formula 1-season on Friday. The fast Dutchman finished on the Albert Park circuit in fifth during the first free practice. Reigning world champion Lewis Hamilton finished first in his Mercedes. Daniil Kvyat came in second for Red Bull Racing, ahead of his team mate Daniel Ricciardo, who claimed third.</p>

<p>When the lights turn green at the end of the pitlane, for the first time in 2016, it is cloudy and the track is wet. Sebastian Vettel is the first to venture out on the full wets. Max also takes to the track pretty early. For his first installation lap, he has gone out on the intermediates but comes back in after that lap. With a 1:44.037, Nico Rosberg is the first one to put a timed lap down in 2016.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Mar 2016 04:36:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/P-20160318-00059_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-3c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2434&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Predicts Max' fastest lap and win the Verstappen Exact cap!</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2432&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with the Verstappen web shop, Verstappen.nl has issued a contest in which the Max Verstappen driver’s cap (priced at € 34,95) can be won during this first round of the season. The cap, featuring the Exact logo, can only be purchased from the Verstappen webshop.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Mar 2016 20:49:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Algemene_Max_Fotos/STR16024-3e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2432&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>STR Olym-PicknMix Games: round 1</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2431&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>As the 2016 F1 season gets underway, Scuderia Toro Rosso introduces the “STR Olym-PicknMix Games”: Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz will pick a different challenge each time and go head to head in 21 games. Before each Grand Prix this season, a new battle between the two youngsters will be available to watch. Below the first round!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Mar 2016 11:56:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Presentatie_STR11_Barcelona/_JMP2921-12f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2431&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max looks ahead to Australian GP: "I just can't wait to go back"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2430&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>It’s finally here! The first race weekend of the 2016 season is almost upon us and we are looking forward to the cars driving out on track again at the Albert Park in Melbourne, kicking-off what will be the longest season in the history of Formula 1. Max is ready to return to his STR11 cockpit, in the Australian Grand Prix.</p>

<p>"Last year's Australian GP was a very special weekend for me: I was so excited to be taking part in my first ever Formula 1 Grand Prix! The parts of the circuit that standout for me are turn 1, where you arrive quite fast – or at least that was my feeling back then, as it was all very new to me! – and it's bumpy in the braking area, so I remember that I found it a bit difficult to get the braking right for that turn. Other things I remember was halfway through the lap, when you arrive to turn 10, I could see a lot of fans there, sitting on the grass – they are so passionate and it's so nice to see! At that same point I was also able to see part of the beautiful city.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Mar 2016 11:37:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/5_S0247723-9f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2430&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Helmut Marko: "Let's see what Max delivers"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2429&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In an interview with Formula1.com, Red Bull’s motorsport consultant Helmut Marko is asked: at Scuderia Toro Rosso you have two extremely fast youngsters in Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz. Will running a 2015-spec Ferrari engine slow them down?</p>

<p>“They are happy to have this engine rather than none at all. And I could imagine that they will land in front of Red Bull Racing at the start of the season - probably until midseason - because the power difference is still that significant. In midseason probably the performance will drop, as you cannot further develop the 2015 engine”, replies Marko.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Mar 2016 11:23:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160303-00114_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-19e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2429&lang=en]]></link>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
